Rasmus Persson

SENIOR DATA CONSULTANT · DATA SCIENTIST

Edinsvägen 3, 131 45 Nacka, Sweden

[(+46) 0720850071 | ■ rasmus@persson.io | persson-io | rasmus-persson

Summary.

Data professional with 7+ years of experience in data science, data visualization, and data engineering. Thriving taking on new challanges as well as further developing my current skills. My experience combined with desire to learn and grow makes me able to take on any challange.

Skills

Data Science LangChain, Ollama, Pandas, Spark, Scikit-learn, Databricks, Vertex AI, Keras, PyTorch, XGBoost, Cloudera, SAS Enterprise Miner **Data Engineer** SQL, Redshift, GraphQL, REST API, FastAPI, Flask, AWS, GCP, Docker, Kubernetes, Rancher, AzureDevOps, BigQuery, SAS DI Studio

Visualization Tableau, Power BI, SAS VA, PowerPoint, Streamlit

Programming Python, SAS, R, JavaScript, Julia, Scala

Languages English, Swedish

Experience

ten10 Sweden

Data Consultant May 2023 - Present

 Leading the partnership with Databricks, setting up a sandbox and training program. This led to 30% of the company receiving Databricks certifications

• Developed a Streamlit dashboard for viewing key metrics, now used by 100% of the company

Finansinspektionen Sweden

DATA ENGINEER (CONSULTANT CONTRACT)

Oct 2023 - Present

- Optimized ETL pipelines, boosting central pipeline performance 8X
- Designed REST/GraphQL API authentication with robust logging, enabeling FI to securly host self-developed web applications
- Restructured regulatory finance data models for enhanced usability

H&M Group Sweden

DATA ANALYST (CONSULTANT CONTRACT)

Jun 2023 - Sep 2023

Sep. 2018 - Jun. 2022

- Created a dashboard from sensitive data sources, providing support for critical decisions
- · Led team analysis and provided senior consultant support. Completed our business critical project on time and without any issues

Dun & Bradstreet Sweden

DATA SCIENTIST Jun. 2022 - Apr. 2023

- Developed data-driven customer segmentation for Nordic sales team reorganization
- Built marketing performance dashboard tracking international ROI informing key strategy decisions for the marketing leadership
- · Created predictive models for customer acquisition and up-selling, enabeling the sales team to contact 100s of new customers

ICA Banken Sweden

• Created a recommender system, increasing customer offer relevance from 32% to 36%

- Developed self-service dashboards for stakeholder data access
- Implemented ETL systems for public data and usage analytics
- Reduced marketing mail volume by 50%, saving 300,000 SEK monthly by training a model to predict the response rate
- Recruited and mentored graduate students in machine learning research

Education

Stockholm University Sweden

BSC IN MATHEMATICS 2020 - 2021

Stockholm University Sweden

BSc in Business Administration and Economic

2015 - 2018

· Vice Chairman of the Finance Society